Osborne Family Papers
Osborne Family Papers
- Legal records
  - Suits
    - Wayne County Bank v. Folts and others, 1841 (Box 314)
    - Wetzel v. Osborne, undated (Box 314)
    - Wheeler v. Clipper Mower & Reaper Co., 1871 (Box 314)
    - Wilson v. New York Evening Journal, 1910 (Box 314)
    - Wright v. Cayuga County Bank, 1853 (Box 314)
    - Wright v. Eldred, 1885 (Box 314)
    - Wright v. Johnson, 1858 (Box 314)
- Memorabilia
  - General
    - Almy, Frederic, 1921-1923 (Box 315)
    - Cayuga County War Memorial, 1925 (Box 315)
    - Devens, Charles, 1863-1891 (Box 315)
    - Feinberg, Richard J., 1901-1903 (Box 315)
    - Garrison, Ellen (Wright)
      - School Records
        - English composition book (Vol. 188), 1856 (Box 315)
        - German composition book (Vol. 189), 1862 (Box 315)
        - Latin exercise book (Vol. 190), 1857 (Box 315)
        - Penmanship exercise books (Vols. 191-192), 1855; 2 volumes (Box 315)
    - O'Connor, James J., 1907-1912 (Box 315)
    - Osborne, Agnes (Devens)
      - Miscellaneous, 1883-1896 (Box 315)
      - Autograph book (Vol. 193), 1875-1880 (Box 315)
      - Monogram dye "ADO", circa 1890 (Box 315)
      - Purse, circa 1890 (Box 315)
    - Osborne, David Munson
      - Miscellaneous, 1845-1886 (Box 315)
      - Scrapbooks (Vol. 194), 1886 (Oversize 7)
      - Tray and medal, 1930 (Box 316)
    - Osborne, David Munson II
      - Miscellaneous, 1876-1909 (Box 316)
      - School Records, 1894-1903 (Box 316)
    - Osborne, Eliza (Wright)
      - Miscellaneous, 1845-1886 (Box 316)
      - Address book (Vol. 195), 1908 (Box 316)
    - Osborne, Frederik, 1945 (Box 316)
    - Osborne, Lillie (Raben-Levetzau), 1931 (Box 316)
    - Osborne, Lithgow
      - Miscellaneous (Box 316)
      - Appointment books (Vols. 196-198), 1941-1943; 3 volumes (Box 316)
      - Appointment books (Vols. 199-210), 1945-1956; 12 volumes (Box 317)
      - Autobiography: Transcript of taped interviews, 1952-1953 (Box 317)
      - Biographical, 1948 (Box 317)
      - Blueprints for residence, Fitch Avenue, Auburn, circa 1923 (Tube 2)
      - Itineraries, 1947 (Box 317)
      - Medals, pins and ribbons (Box 318)
      - Newspaper clippings and separates, 1919-1951 (Box 318)
      - Passports, 1919-1952; 4 items (Box 318)
      - Political records
        - Miscellaneous, 1908-1942 (Box 318)
        - Doyle and Rich petition, undated (Box 318)
        - Financial, 1928-1930 (Box 318)
      - Phonodisc, "The People Against John Taber", 1942 (Box 318)
      - Press releases, 1923-1965 (Box 319)
      - School records, 1927-1909 (Box 319)
      - Scrapbooks
        - Auburn: Views and reminiscences (Vol. 211), 1900-1932 (Box 319)
        - Conservation (Vol. 212), 1933-1937 (Oversize 4)
        - Editorials (Vol. 213), 1933 (Oversize 5)
        - New York State Crime Commission (Vol. 214), 1951-1952 (Oversize 6)
        - New York State Crime Commission (Vol. 215), 1952-1953 (Oversize 6)
        - Politics (Vol. 216), 1903-1906 (Oversize 7)
        - Politics (Vol. 217), 1929-1931 (Oversize 8)
        - Politics (Vol. 218), 1950 (Box 319)
        - School days (Vol. 219), 1903-1909 (Oversize 9)
        - School days (Vol. 220), 1909-1911 (Oversize 10)
        - Harvard (Vol. 221), 1911-1913 (Box 320)
        - Harvard (Vol. 222), 1913-1914 (Box 321)
        - Travel, (Vol. 223), 1914-1920 (Oversize 11)
    - Osborne, Lithgow Devens, 1935 (Box 321)
    - Osborne, Richard
      - Biographical, 1939-1946 (Box 321)
      - School records, 1935 (Box 321)
    - Osborne, Robert K., 1909-1913 (Box 321)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott
      - Miscellaneous, 1880-1926 (Box 321)
      - Address books (Vols. 224-226), 1905-1906; 3 volumes (Box 322)
      - Appointment books (Vols. 227-247), 1898-1913; 1917-1924; 21 volumes (Box 322)
      - Award for prison exhibit, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1915 (Oversize 12)
      - Biographical, 1880-1926 (Box 322)
      - Card file of names and addresses, undated (Box 323)
      - Cartoon, Sing Sing, hand-drawn, circa 1915 (Oversize 12)
      - Certificate of election to Pierian Sodality of Harvard College, 1880 (Box 323)
      - Commissions
        - Miscellaneous, 1909-1924 (Box 323)
        - New York State Fish, Forest and Game Commissioner, 1911 (Oversize 1)
      - Funeral, 1926 (Box 324)
      - Gavel, inscribed, 1903 (Box 324)
      - Invitations, 1900-1920 (Box 324)
      - Itineraries, 1920-1924 (Box 324)
      - Log book, "Motor car, Green Dragon" (Vol. 248), 1907 (Box 324)
      - Medals, pins and ribbons, circa 1880-1920 (Box 324)
      - Membership certificate, Chamber of Commerce, Auburn, N.Y., 1901 (Oversize 12)
      - Musical notation: Quartets, concertos and choral arrangements, 1896 (Oversize 5)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1891-1926 (Box 324)
      - Notebooks (Vol. 249-255), 1877-1878; 1886-1895,; circa 1912,; 1926-1927; 7 volumes (Box 325)
      - Obituaries, 1926-1927 (Box 325)
      - Political papers
        - Miscellaneous, 1900-1926 (Box 325)
        - The Democratic League of New York, 1909-1911 (Box 325)
        - Democratic National Convention, 1912 (Box 325)
        - Democratic State Conference, 1906 (Box 326)
        - Democratic State Convention, Buffalo, 1906 (Box 326)
        - Democratic State Convention, Rochester, 1910 (Box 326)
        - Democratic State Convention, Syracuse, 1912 (Box 326)
        - Finances, 1906-1907 (Box 326)
        - National Democratic Party, 1896 (Box 326)
        - Voters lists, 1896; 1905; 2 folders (Box 326)
      - "Portrait of Lt. Commander T. M. Osborne C.O. of Portsmouth Navy Prison, painted at the prison Sept 1919 by Orlando Rouland", painting (Oversize 12)
      - Portrait, unidentified (Oversize 1)
      - School records
        - Miscellaneous, 1870-1924 (Box 326)
        - Diploma: Harvard, 1884 (Oversize 1)
        - French exercise book (Vol. 256), 1874 (Box 326)
        - Harvard lecture notes
          - Fine arts (Vols. 257-258), 1882-1884; 2 volumes (Box 327)
          - History (Vols. 259-264), 1881-1883; 3 folders (6 volumes) (Box 327)
          - History (Vols. 265-267), 1884; 3 volumes (Box 328)
          - Music (Vols. 268-271), 1883-1884; 4 volumes (Box 328)
          - Philosophy (Vols. 272-273), 1882-1883; 2 volumes (Box 328)
          - Political Economy (Vol. 274), 1884 (Box 328)
        - The A.D. Club of Harvard University, 1837-1916 (Vol. 275) (Box 328)
        - Class of 1884, Harvard: Twenty-fifth anniversary report of the secretary (Vol. 276), 1909 (Box 329)
      - Scrapbooks
        - Miscellaneous
          - (Vol. 277), 1893-1901 (Oversize 13)
          - (Vol. 278), 1898-1902 (Box 330)
          - (Vol. 279), 1926-1936 (Oversize 14)
        - Harvard College (Vol. 280), 1881-1884 (Box 331)
        - Politics
          - (Vol. 281-282), 1898-1902; 2 volumes (Box 332)
          - (Vol. 283-284), 1902-1903; 2 volumes (Box 333)
          - (Vol. 285-286), 1903-1904; 2 volumes (Box 334)
          - (Vol. 287-288), 1904-1905; 2 volumes (Box 335)
          - (Vol. 289-290), 1904-1905; 2 volumes (Box 336)
          - (Vol. 291-292), 1905-1906; 2 volumes (Box 337)
          - (Vol. 293-294), 1906; 2 volumes (Box 338)
          - (Vol. 295-296), 1906-1907; 2 volumes (Box 339)
          - (Vol. 297), 1907-1908 (Oversize 17)
          - (Vol. 298), 1911-1912 (Box 340)
          - (Vol. 299-300), 1911-1916; 2 volumes (Box 341)
          - (Vol. 301), 1919-1925 (Oversize 3)
        - Prisons
          - (Vol. 302), 1913-1914 (Box 342)
          - (Vol. 303), 1915 (Oversize 3)
          - (Vol. 304), 1915-1916 (Oversize 2)
          - (Vol. 305), 1916-1918 (Oversize 2)
          - (Vol. 306), 1914-1926 (Box 342)
        - Public Service Commission, First District (Vol. 307), 1907; scrapbook (Oversize 8)
        - Public Service Commission, First District, 1907; box of loose clippings, associated with Vol. 307 (Oversize 16)
        - Public Service Commission, Second District (Vol. 308), 1907; scrapbook (Oversize 15)
      - Sketches, Thomas Mott Osborne, small painting "Ellen", 1914 (Box 343)
      - Testimonials
        - Miscellaneous, 1911 (Box 343)
        - Signed by inmates of Auburn Prison, 1914 (Box 343)
        - Columbia Rope Co., 1927 (Box 343)
      - Travel, Europe, 1911 (Box 343)
    - Osborne Family
      - Miscellaneous (Vols. 309-310), undated; 2 volumes (Box 343)
      - Book orders, 1875-1924 (Box 343)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1845-1930 (Box 343)
    - Osborne Memorial
      - Miscellaneous, 1908-1945 (Box 343)
      - Specifications, 1929 (Box 344)
    - Oxford, N.Y., 1831 (Box 344)
    - Sexton, Lawrence E., fl. 1910 (Box 344)
    - Storrow, Helen (Osborne), 1915-1944 (Box 344)
    - Storrow, James Jackson Jr., 1885-1926 (Box 344)
    - Trask, Katrina, 1922; newspaper clippings (Box 344)
    - Valentine, Olivia (Osborne), 1940 (Box 344)
    - Wright, David
      See also Communications and writings: Writings: Wright, David (Boxes 236 and 254).
      - Appointment books (Vols. 311-315), 1838-1841; 1844-1848; 12 volumes (Box 344)
      - Notebooks (Vols. 316-322), 1840-1873; 7 volumes (Box 344)
      - School records (Vol. 323-326), 1858-1861; penmanship exercise books; 4 volumes (Box 344)
    - Wright family, undated (Box 344)
  - Genealogies
    See also family trees, at end of Biographical History section (above).
    - Andrews, Francis, fl. 1663 (Box 344)
    - Barlow, John Sr., fl. 1674 (Box 344)
    - Barlow, John Jr., fl. 1691 (Box 344)
    - Bartram, Ebenezer, 1699-1769 (Box 344)
    - Bartram, Ebenezer Jr., 1732-1783 (Box 344)
    - Bartram, John, fl. 1740 (Box 344)
    - Bennett, James, fl. 1659 (Box 344)
    - Burr, Andrew, fl. 1710 (Box 344)
    - Burr, Jehue, fl. 1654 (Box 344)
    - Burr, John, fl. 1650 (Box 344)
    - Burr, John, 1672-1759 (Box 345)
    - Burr, John, fl. 1690 (Box 345)
    - Burr, John, 1698-1752 (Box 345)
    - Burr, Nathaniel, fl. 1665 (Box 345)
    - Coffin family, 1600-1750 (Box 345)
    - Couch, Simon, 1633-1688 (Box 345)
    - Couch, Simon Jr., fl. 1713 (Box 345)
    - Fitch, Thomas, fl. 1704 (Box 345)
    - Goodyear, Stephen, fl. 1638 (Box 345)
    - Hanford, Thomas, 1621-1693 (Box 345)
    - Hawley, Ebenezer, fl. 1675 (Box 345)
    - Hawley, Joseph, 1603-1690 (Box 345)
    - Lockwood, Robert, fl. 1658 (Box 345)
    - Miles, Deacon Richard, fl. 1666 (Box 345)
    - Osborne, Daniel, 1725-1804 (Box 345)
    - Osborne, Daniel Jr., 1760-1801 (Box 345)
    - Osborne, David, fl. 1679 (Box 345)
    - Osborne, John, 1650-1709 (Box 345)
    - Osborne, John Hall, 1791-1843 (Box 345)
    - Osborne, Richard, fl. 1612 (Box 345)
    - Osborne, Samuel, 1680-1752 (Box 345)
    - Osborne Family, 1600-1750
      - Vol. I, holograph, bound (Vol. 327) (Box 345)
      - Vol. II, holograph, bound (Vol. 328) (Box 346)
      - Notes by Thomas Mott Osborne (Box 346)
    - Osborne, Wright, Lithgow, Devens, Coffin and other families (Vol. 329), 1600-1900 (Box 346)
    - Pelham, Peter, 1785-1826 (Box 346)
    - Pinkney, Philip, fl. 1689 (Box 346)
    - Sturges, Jonathan, fl. 1711 (Box 346)
    - Wakeman, Francis, fl. 1626 (Box 346)
    - Wakeman, John, 1601-1661 (Box 346)
    - Wakeman, Joseph, 1670-1726 (Box 346)
    - Wakeman, Samuel, 1634-1691 (Box 346)
    - Ward, Andrew, fl. 1659 (Box 346)
    - Ward, William, fl. 1660 (Box 346)
    - Wheeler, Thomas, fl. 1654 (Box 346)
    - Williams, John, fl. 1725 (Box 346)
    - Wright Family, 1750-1950 (Box 346)
  - Photographs
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified
      - People (Box 347)
      - Views (Box 347)
    - Auburn, N.Y., 1870-1930 (Box 347)
    - Auburn City Hall, 1930; engravings; 4 items (Box 347)
    - Barnes, Henry, 1922 (Box 347)
    - Berlin, Germany, 1914 (Box 347)
    - Devens, Charles, 1865-1880 (Box 347)
    - Devens, Richard, undated (Box 347)
    - Devens, Mary, circa 1880 (Box 347)
    - Eliot, Charles, circa 1906 (Box 347)
    - Europe, 1907 (Box 347)
    - Europe, views of tour in the "Green Dragon", 1907 (Box 348)
    - Europe, views of tour in the "Green Dragon", 1907 (Box 349)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd, 1871 (Box 350)
    - George Junior Republic, 1895-1910 (Box 350)
    - George Junior Republic, circa 1910; 2 items (Oversize 1)
    - Germany
      - American Legation Staff, circa 1915 (Box 350)
      - Ruhleben Prisoner of War Camp, circa 1915 (Box 350)
    - Hamlen, Paul M., circa 1890 (Box 350)
    - Harris, Emily (Osborne), 1870-1890 (Box 350)
    - Hill, W.L., 1917 (Box 350)
    - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1910-1912 (Box 350)
    - Klipfel Family, circa 1915 (Box 350)
    - Lithgow, William, undated (Box 350)
    - Machinery
      - Agricultural, circa 1880 (Box 350)
      - Saw mill, circa 1870 (Box 350)
    - Military, 1928-1945 (Box 350)
    - Mott, Lucretia (Coffin), 1875-1879 (Box 350)
    - Osborne, Agnes (Devens)
      - Miscellaneous, 1880-1896 (Box 351)
      - Portraits, 1880-1896 (Box 351)
    - Osborne, Caroline (Bulkley), circa 1870 (Box 351)
    - Osborne, David Munson
      - Portraits
        - Miscellaneous, 1875-1886 (Box 351)
        - Engraving plate, circa 1880 (Box 351)
      - Residence, Auburn, 1880 (Box 351)
    - Osborne, David Munson and family, 1860-1885 (Box 351)
    - Osborne, David Munson II, 1890-1950 (Box 351)
    - Osborne, Eliza (Wright), 1860-1910 (Box 351)
    - Osborne, John, circa 1890 (Box 351)
    - Osborne, Lillie (Raben-Levetzau), 1918-1930 (Box 351)
    - Osborne, Lithgow
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1935; mounted wide-angle views with canoe; 4 items (Oversize 1)
      - Portraits, 1915-1950 (Box 352)
      - U.S. Ambassador to Norway, 1944-1946 (Box 352)
    - Osborne, Lithgow and wife, 1918-1946 (Box 352)
    - Osborne, Lithgow and children, 1920-1940 (Box 352)
    - Osborne, Lithgow and others, 1915-1940 (Box 352)
    - Osborne, Mary (Morse), circa 1940 (Box 352)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott
      - Miscellaneous, 1895-1926 (Box 352)
      - Portraits, 1875-1926 (Box 352)
      - Portraits, circa 1915; 2 items (Oversize 1)
      - Portraits, circa 1900; engraving plates (Box 353)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott and sons
      - Miscellaneous, 1895-1925 (Box 353)
      - Portraits, 1886-1895 (Box 353)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott and family, circa 1890 (Box 353)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott and others, 1885-1925 (Box 353)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott, 1921; film stills, The Right Way (Box 353)
    - Osborne Family, 1885-1895 (Box 354)
    - Osborne Memorial, 1927 (Box 354)
    - Sing Sing Prison
      - "Tom Brown Honor Camp", 1914 (Box 354)
      - Return of Osborne, 1916 (Box 354)
    - Storrow, Helen (Osborne), 1880-1900 (Box 354)
    - Storrow family, circa 1900 (Box 354)
    - Valentine, Olivia (Osborne), 1940 (Box 354)
    - Willow Point, circa 1890 (Box 354)
    - Wright Family, circa 1855 (Box 354)
  - Photograph albums
    - Osborne, Agnes (Devens)and others (Vol. 330), circa 1880 (Box 354)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott and sons (Vol. 331), 1887-1896 (Box 355)
    - Osborne Family
      - Caribbean travel (Vol. 332), circa 1910 (Box 355)
      - World tour (Vols. 333-335), 1910-1911 (Box 356)
      - Children (Vol. 336), 1890-1895 (Box 357)
      - Outings (album, Vol. 337), 1904 (Box 357)
      - Portraits (album, Vol. 338), 1860-1900 (Box 357)
    - Osborne Family (glass negatives), 1885-1900 (Box 358)